Fernando J Soares



1000 Felipe Bender St Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil CEP 95660-000 +55 (51) 9 9918 7006 biofsdev@gmail.com

Self-taught I.T. hobbyist, cybersecurity undergraduate student, licensed Biologist

PROFILE

Data driven, science-oriented professional. Since 1986 I have been involved in information technology, teaching, learning and contributing to the field, especially where it intersects with science and biodiversity. For the past 13 years I have been the lead biologist at Tres Coroas townhall. During this time, I have developed my own company, and a few of my own projects. An online handbook APP for better practices in urban trees management, a system for implementing and monitoring public policies, and a draft project for an environmental market platform.

LANGUAGES	ENGLISH: ADVANCED	PORTUGUESE: NATIVE	SPANISH: INTERMEDIATE	
SKILLS	PYTHON / DJANGO *** DOCUMENTATION **** GIT ****	WEB DEV. *** SQL / POSTGRESQL *** DATABASE DESIGN ***	DATA COLLECTION **** DATA CLEANSING *** DATA SECURITY ***	

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 TO DATE - BUSINESS OWNER

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

QUADRAT ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANCY LTD. — as a business owner and environmental consultant since 2010, when I returned to Brazil from 5.5 years stay in the USA, mostly developing environmental impact assessment studies and analyzing their respective technical documentations. My dream project for this company is to develop an environmental services marketplace platform where engineers, biologists, geologists and all highly qualified professionals can go for support, know-how and sales.

2012 TO DATE - LEAD BIOLOGIST

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

CITY TOWN HALL OF TRES COROAS — As Lead Biologist I have been working extensively with environmental licensing, biodiversity management and urban trees management. Recently I have been working on a bioregional project (watershed based), developing a system to accommodate data pertaining to several smaller projects across 30 municipalities.

2005 - 2010 - RESEARCH ASSISTANT / ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

Melbourne, FL, USA

FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY — While pursuing my Ph.D., I have worked assisting research with data collection, wrangling, cleansing and analysis for a mobile app to help Alzheimer's caretakers, and for a nationwide environmental education assessment project. I have also taught University Experience, and Survey of Science for undergraduate students.

EDUCATION

1988 – 2002 UNIVERSITY OF THE SINOS RIVER VALLEY – UNISINOS

Sao Leopoldo, RS - Brazil

B. Sc. Biology (Graduate and Licensed Biologist)

Canoas, RS - Brazil

2003 – 2005 LUTERAN UNIVERSITY OF BRAZIL – ULBRA

Master of Science Education for Sustainable Development

Melbourne, FL - USA

2005 - 2010 FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY A.b.D. Environmental Education E.Ed. Interdisciplinary Studies

Tres Coroas, RS - Brazil

2024 - to date UNIASSELVI

Tech. Information Security

SOCIAL



inkedin.com/in/fsoares/



@biofsphere



FOERMER EXPERIENCE

From high school graduation as a Chemistry Technician, I moved on to the field of education and for half of my career, I was a high school and/or college teacher working in private and public schools. During this time, I also taught BASIC and LOGO programming languages.